I realized my enthusiasm for this project is a bit insane, but I have to tell you that I am very satisfied
비트를 향한 제 열정이 좀 지나치긴 했지만 결과에 아주 만족해요
It's rare that you come up with a project like this that has so many moving parts and is technically
이런 프로젝트는 드물죠 이렇게 움직이는 부분이 많고
quite complex and has a lot of substance to it, but have such a simple and tangible outcome as our
기술적으로 꽤 복잡하고 실질적인 것도 많지만 푸시 알림처럼 단순하고 실질적인
push notification for a good deal.
결과를 얻었어요
There is something beyond the king of the notification that really makes this very satisfying indeed.
통지의 제왕 이상의 뭔가가 이 영화를 아주 만족스럽게 만들어요
But one point that I wanted to make about it, perhaps a more, more seriously, is to point out that
다만 이에 관해 한 가지 강조하고 싶은 점은 이 문제를 해결하기
this sort of template that we've got here for solving this problem is something that you can apply to
위해 준비한 이 템플릿은 여러분이 이미 생각해 둔 유사한
a lot of other similar kinds of business problems and startup ideas and commercial problems that you
사업 문제나 스타트업 아이디어 상업적 문제에 적용할 수 있다는
might even have been thinking about already.
거죠
I mean, to give you something that comes to mind right away is that when I was looking on hugging face
즉, 바로 떠오르는 것을 말씀드리자면 얼굴을 안는
for the data for this this project, for the Amazon pricing data, I also came across a bunch of data
것을 볼 때 이 프로젝트 아마존 가격 데이터를 볼 때 회사들의 연간 리포트가
that that has company reports, annual reports from companies and shows how that relates to the change
있는 많은 데이터를 보게 되었는데요 리포트가 나온 당일과 그 후 며칠간의 주가 변화와
in share price on the day and the few days after the report comes out, which is a very interesting
어떻게 관련되어 있는지 보여줍니다 아주 흥미로운 데이터 집합이죠
And it occurs to me that whilst this is more of a stretch, it is also obviously a bigger opportunity
이건 좀 억지스럽긴 하지만 그걸 풀 방법을 찾는다면 더 큰 기회가
if you can find a way to crack it.
되겠죠
If there's a way to build a proprietary model that's able to look at that and make some prediction about
소유 모델을 구축할 방법이 있다면 그걸 살펴보고 회사의 보고서가 공개된 결과로
what will happen to the share price as a result of a company's report being published.
주가가 어떻게 될지 예측할 수 있는 거죠
And you could imagine then having a scanner agent that scans the new company reports being being being
스캐너 요원이 출시 예정인 신규 회사를 스캔하는 걸 상상해 보세요
And so you can really see the very similar agent workflow that you would adapt for that kind of of of
아주 유사한 에이전트 워크플로우를 보실 수 있습니다 그런 종류의 문제에 적응하는
problem.
거죠
Now, of course, I will tell you that any trading decisions that you make are entirely at your own
물론 당신이 내리는 모든 거래 결정은 전적으로 당신 책임이고
risk, and I have nothing to do with them at all.
나와는 전혀 상관이 없어요
And obviously no one has yet cracked that problem of being able to build an automated AI system that
물론 아직 아무도 그 문제를 해결하지 못했죠 회사 보고서를 읽고 그 결과로
can do things like read company reports and make, uh, trading decisions robust trading decisions as
탄탄한 의사 결정을 내리는 자동화된 인공지능 시스템을 개발하는 거요
But it seems like a serious, a very, um, important challenge to take on.
하지만 이건 아주 심각하고 중요한 도전 같아요
And I wanted to point that out because it shows you how similar that is in terms of the the bits and
그걸 지적하고 싶었어요 얼마나 비슷한지 보여주거든요 퍼즐 조각
pieces of the puzzle that you would look at if you wanted to do that.
같은 면에서요 그걸 원한다면 볼 수 있죠
So that could certainly be a big challenge, if nothing else, just for the interest of seeing what
그러니 큰 도전이 될 수 있죠 다른 건 없더라도요 어떤 일이 일어나는지 흥미를 위해 그런 종류의 데이터에서 신호를
happens and seeing whether you can find signal in that kind of data and using it as an opportunity to
찾을 수 있는지 보고 유사한 에이전트 워크플로우를 구축할 기회로
build a similar agent workflow.
활용하기 위해서요
Okay.
네
Anyway, with that, let's move to the last slide of this week, which is of this sorry, not of this
어쨌든, 이번 주의 마지막 슬라이드로 넘어가죠 이∙∙∙ 아니, 이번 주가 아니라 오늘의
week, of this day, which is to tell you that there is now one day left.
슬라이드요 이제 하루 남았다는 걸 알려드리려고요
There is one final day, week eight, day five, which will be the conclusion of this course.
8주 차, 5일 차인 마지막 날이 이 코스의 마지막 날이죠
And you don't want to miss it.
놓치면 후회하실 거예요
Uh, before I tell you what you'll do, then just to remind you, at this point you can generate code
여러분이 뭘 할지 말씀드리기 전에 상기시켜 드리자면 이 시점에서 프론티어 모델로
and text with frontier models, with open source models, using hugging face, using APIs with tools,
코드와 텍스트를 생성할 수 있습니다 오픈 소스 모델로요 얼굴을 끌어안는 것과 도구를 이용한 API
structured outputs, rag with assistance from from Gradio.
구조적 출력물들을 이용하죠 GRadio의 도움을 받아서요
You can follow that strategy we went through to solve problems including curating your data, which
문제 해결에 사용한 전략을 따르세요 데이터 큐레이팅을 포함해서요
is hard and grueling, but perhaps the single most important step.
힘들고 고된 일이지만 가장 중요한 단계죠
Um, making your baseline model and fine tuning a frontier model.
기본 모델을 만들고 개척지 모델을 세밀하게 조정하는 거죠
And then you can Select and train an open source model.
오픈 소스 모델을 선택하고 훈련할 수 있어요
And we did it.
그리고 해냈죠
We beat the frontier when we did that.
개척지를 뛰어넘은 거죠
You can deploy models to production.
모델을 생산에 배포할 수 있어요
Now you can use modal to to put something up there on the cloud.
Modal을 이용해 클라우드에 뭔가를 놓을 수 있어요
You can also productionize your code in other ways and prepare it into something that can be run in
다른 방법으로 코드를 제작할 수도 있어요 프로덕션 환경에서 실행될 수
production environments.
있도록 준비하는 거죠
And now you can build agentic workflows with planning memory, databases and multiple agents working
기획 메모리와 데이터베이스, 그리고 여러 에이전트가 함께 복잡한 작업을 수행하는
together to take a complex task and break it down.
에이전트 워크플로를 구축할 수 있어요.
And so that brings us to preparing for tomorrow.
그래서 내일을 준비하는 거예요
Tomorrow, of course, we're going to be building a user interface, which is going to be glorious because
내일은 사용자 인터페이스를 만들 겁니다 그레이디오에 있으니 아주
it's in Gradio.
훌륭하죠
Uh, we'll also be looking at the fact that today when we ran that workflow, you'll notice that it
오늘 워크플로우를 실행했을 때 실행된 후 완료된 걸
ran and then it completed.
볼 수 있죠
So it's not really autonomous and it doesn't keep running and have it still relies on the human to press
자동적으로 계속 작동하지 않고 매번 사람이 눌러야 하는
it each time.
거죠
So we need to fix that of course.
물론 그걸 고쳐야겠죠
So we will do both of those things tomorrow.
내일 둘 다 할 거예요
And once they are done, that will leave you in a position where you will have mastered AI and LM engineering.
그 과정이 끝나면 인공지능과 LM 공학에 통달한 상태가 되죠
And I can't wait for that point.
그 순간이 기다려져요
I hope that you are both excited and proud and I will see you there.
기대와 자부심을 느끼시길 바라요 거기서 뵐게요